<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DevBThom Blog</title>
    <link>https://devbthom.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DevBThom Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 16:07:27 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://devbthom.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Going to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://devbthom.com/posts/going-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 16:07:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devbthom.com/posts/going-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Update 1 - Hugo and Where I&amp;rsquo;m At Why Hugo? I think that over time my web developer journey has become more about doing and figuring out what I want to do. I know that building Full-Stack Applications is an end goal, but in the meanwhile, I want to be able to produce value otherwise. I know that the community, and most people, could use someone who is keeping a pulse on the internet for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DoctorOfficeIT</title>
      <link>https://devbthom.com/posts/doctorofficeit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 21:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devbthom.com/posts/doctorofficeit/</guid>
      <description>This is a project I had in the works for a period of over 4/5 months. My goal was to replicate the site, which I did, and then touch up that recreation to bring it modern features. I also wanted to give the home page a bit of a facelift, and fix other various minor errors. I am happy with how it came out! The experience taught me about hosting, BootStrap 5, and semantic HTML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House of Pho</title>
      <link>https://devbthom.com/posts/house-of-pho/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 21:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devbthom.com/posts/house-of-pho/</guid>
      <description>The vision for this project was to re-create the site staying committed to the basic sitemap of the current site. To do this, we simplified the sitemap even more and decided to work on a single page site. The only external tools used is jQuery and Google Fonts.
The 3 key points for the new site:
Theming and Site Color Navigation and Footer Fixes Responsive Web Design Theme and Color The old site used a color pallet of light green, red, and white.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Freelance Workflow</title>
      <link>https://devbthom.com/posts/basic-freelance-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 20:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devbthom.com/posts/basic-freelance-workflow/</guid>
      <description>What Workflow? One major shift in terms of the way I want to further pursue my ideal web development dreams has to do with my workflow. I think that while I was focusing on too many different things, I had nothing to a point of being extremely comfortable. I want to create, manage, and innovate a system for myself that allows me to best invest my time in web development. I hope you likewise find a system for yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Express Middleware: A Dummy Overview</title>
      <link>https://devbthom.com/posts/express-middleware-a-dummy-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devbthom.com/posts/express-middleware-a-dummy-overview/</guid>
      <description>Specific aspects of Web Development elude me even after getting my Associate&amp;rsquo;s in Web Development. Specifically moreover, a lot of the back-end terminology, tools, and concepts. Middleware started off as something which eluded me, but hopefully, I can clarify it and put it in a way that my brain understood it.
Middleware Express provides some key points I want to highlight in this condensed lesson provided by expressjs.com. Middleware can:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding WordPress</title>
      <link>https://devbthom.com/posts/understanding-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 20:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devbthom.com/posts/understanding-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>One thing I found confusing about WordPress was how themes, plugins, and widgets can change so much over the management of a site. For one theme you have an editor, for another one you have customization, and so on. I think one thing that was made clear to me from the Udemy course I took regarding WordPress is to find your way to make one thing, then add on. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to learn how to use the new editor, themes, widgets, plugins, and all the other new features at once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress for Beginners - Master Wordpress Quickly</title>
      <link>https://devbthom.com/posts/wordpress-for-beginners-master-wordpress-quickly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 19:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devbthom.com/posts/wordpress-for-beginners-master-wordpress-quickly/</guid>
      <description>When looking to add to your toolkit as a web developer, WordPress is a great place to start and add to your tool kit. I earned my Associate in Applied Science in Web Development and wanted to work ASAP. As I started looking at what I could do on my own I realized my skills and potential would be limited if I didn&amp;rsquo;t learn about the platform that hosts 33% of websites!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step By Step</title>
      <link>https://devbthom.com/posts/step-by-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 21:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devbthom.com/posts/step-by-step/</guid>
      <description>I can comprehend what small businesses owner go through by the experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve had working with them. I have seen both sides of the coin in terms of what big and small business does. I know that often small business owners can be busy all the time, having unrelenting pressure to work because of the absurdly high failure rate. I originally thought it was 90% as mentioned at the start of the article, but 70%, not too bad&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Mission</title>
      <link>https://devbthom.com/posts/my-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 18:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devbthom.com/posts/my-mission/</guid>
      <description>I think that a lot of the time, web development can be an end goal for someone, a means to a purpose. I am in that same boat but want to use it as a means to a degree of fulfillment. I view what I want to do as a path that has different options. A corporate job, passionate software developers, freelance nomads, etc. I see myself as someone pursuing that freelance nomad ideal with the addition of wanting to help as many people as I can.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
